<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>motivation on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in motivation on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why you should write your own Impossible List</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-12-09-why-you-should-write-your-own-impossible-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-12-09-why-you-should-write-your-own-impossible-list/</guid>
      <description>Writing down your goals is extremely helpful for really achieving them. With fixed, terminable goals with fixed intermediate steps, you make it much easier for yourself to really achieve your self-imposed goals.
Today I would like to show you a way to define your goals with the help of the so-called &amp;ldquo;Impossible List&amp;rdquo;. At first glance this list looks like an Impossible List, but it is definitely not: Joel Runyon, the author of the first Impossible List describes the classic Bucket List as a static list that was written at some point in life and usually none of the points written down really affect the life of the creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Running</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-09-23-getting-started-with-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-09-23-getting-started-with-running/</guid>
      <description>If you had told me a year ago that I would run an entire Tough Mudder in a year, I probably would have made fun of you. Well, to be honest, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know about the existence of obstacle course races (OCR) of this kind at the time. If that were the case, I would certainly have been able to motivate myself quickly.
Briefly to my prehistory: I am in my early 20s and have tried various sports since my childhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step Outside Your Comfort Zone!</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-05-31-step-outside-your-comfort-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-05-31-step-outside-your-comfort-zone/</guid>
      <description>We humans tend to make ourselves comfortable. We take the easiest way we can find. But there are so many things we miss this way. In many cases it is the small things that make a big difference. Today I would like to show you how I have taken such a step and what has changed since then.
Photo by Jenny Hill on Unsplash
As a child I did athletics for several years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
