<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windows on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windows on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 18:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bypassing Microsofts Windows Media Creation Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-04-09-bypass-windows-media-creation-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-04-09-bypass-windows-media-creation-tool/</guid>
      <description>Remember when you could simply download official Windows ISO images to burn on DVDs and install? Microsoft now uses this thing called &amp;lsquo;Media Creation Tool&amp;rsquo; to download ISOs, but there&amp;rsquo;s a simple way to bypass this and download actual images.
When searching for Windows10 ISOs, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely find this url, which provides a download for the Media Creation Tool.
 https://www.microsoft.com/de-de/software-download/windows10  But: there&amp;rsquo;s also this url
 https://www.microsoft.com/de-de/software-download/windows10ISO  However, when browsing this site on a windows machine, it automatically redirects you to the first of the pages I linked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing MagicaVoxel on Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-01-20-install-magicavoxel-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-01-20-install-magicavoxel-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>As a programmer with definite lack of visual skills, MagicaVoxel is a gift from God to create usable 3D models. Unfortunately, there is no installation option for Linux on the official website. With the help of Wine it is possible to use MagicaVoxel under Linux. And it really works great!
Installation Prerequisites As I said you need to run Wine. As stated on their landing page, Wine is a compatibility layer that allows Windows applications to run under POSIX-compliant operating systems such as Linux, macOS and BSD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xamarin Debugging over WIFI</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-01-10-debugging-xamarin-apps-on-physical-device-over-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 06:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-01-10-debugging-xamarin-apps-on-physical-device-over-wifi/</guid>
      <description>Xamarin utilizes the Android Debug Bridge (ADB) for debugging on physical devices, which are usually connected over usb. While this feature definitely is useful, it would sometimes be more practical if you could do this over WIFI instead.
Luckily, that is possible! You can simple switch between using USB and TCP/IP for debugging. To get started, you need to connect your device via USB to the computer you&amp;rsquo;re debugging from. I&amp;rsquo;m using Windows, so the commands I&amp;rsquo;ll execute the following commands from the commandline (which runs as an administrator), but since they are adb commands, they should be the same on Linux or macOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling Views in Xamarin</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-12-decoupling-views-in-xamarin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 10:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-12-decoupling-views-in-xamarin/</guid>
      <description>As a software developer, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably stumbled across old source code you&amp;rsquo;ve written from time to time and you&amp;rsquo;ve just been thinking &amp;lsquo;how the hell can someone come up with such bullshit?&amp;rsquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself as an exception regarding this topic and just recently had such a case, which I would like to document in this article. More specifically, I want to discuss the decoupling of views under xamarin. The source I use in this article is available on my GitHub profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P2P Synchronization with Syncthing</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-01-p2p-synchronization-with-syncthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 13:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-01-p2p-synchronization-with-syncthing/</guid>
      <description>Everyone has different programs and tools that they particularly appreciate. One of these programs is syncthing for me, so I will briefly discuss how it works and how it is set up in this article. Syncthing is used to synchronize files between different devices and also supports versioning of these files. Syncthing is available for Windows, Android and as cross-platform wrapper. I personally use it on Windows 10, Arch Linux and Android (via Playstore or FDroid).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Package Management</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-10-10-windows-package-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 11:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-10-10-windows-package-management/</guid>
      <description>As a Windows user with Linux knowledge there are several things under Linux that I would like to have on for Windows. Since a complete switch from Windows to Linux is not feasible for me due to different requirements, I looked for alternatives. An important component of various Linux distributions is their package manager. This article discusses the implementation of such a feature under Windows and shows how it can be used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
