<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to RegEx</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-02-24-introduction-to-regex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-02-24-introduction-to-regex/</guid>
      <description>As a developer you have probably already worked with Regular Expressions. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me and didn&amp;rsquo;t need them too often, you probably googled them up more than you wrote them yourself.
So today I&amp;rsquo;d like to go through the basics of Regex and show you how to build regular expressions and how to write them yourself.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t had anything to do with this topic before, this post is still for you, of course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to program does not have to be easy</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-12-02-learning-to-program-doesnt-have-to-be-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-12-02-learning-to-program-doesnt-have-to-be-easy/</guid>
      <description>I have been asked all too often which programming language to learn first. And I&amp;rsquo;ve heard almost the same number of different opinions. Java or C++? Python or C#? Or maybe C?
High-level programming languages like Java offer the big advantage that the entry hurdle is very low. You can quickly put together a functional application that does what it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to do. The extensive ecosystem allows you to make rapid progress and concentrate on the functionality of your software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building your first API in .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-10-21-your-first-api-net-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-10-21-your-first-api-net-core/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to show you how to develop your first API with .NET Core.
.NET Core is an alternative to the classic .NET Framework. In contrast to the .NET Framework, .NET Core offers a huge advantage: It is platform-independent and therefore compatible with MacOS, Linux and Windows.
The purpose of this article is to build a small REST-based API, which will respond to HTTP GET-requests. Of course you can extend the project according to your own ideas and experiment around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of Code</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-10-14-100-days-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-10-14-100-days-of-code/</guid>
      <description>You might be familiar with the following situation: You are in your first job as a software developer and spend less and less time with your own projects? Or the time you spend on them is generally getting less and less? I have the problem right now and I’ve been thinking about what’s causing it and how I can work on it. Well, the main problem, in my opinion, is that I no longer have the pressure from my studies to learn to take an exam, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Testing</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-08-05-automated-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-08-05-automated-testing/</guid>
      <description>Todays focus is on how you can test your applications automatically to detect bugs early and improve your code quality.
I want to introduce you to the concept of automated testing. In order to make the content accessible to as many users as possible, I will not use code examples and concentrate purely on the underlying idea instead. Once you understand them, you will have no problems implementing the concept in the programming language of your choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency Injection - Overview and Implementation</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-23-dependency-injection-overview-and-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-23-dependency-injection-overview-and-implementation/</guid>
      <description>Especially when you are at the beginning of your career as a software developer, you probably know that: You have already picked up the term &amp;ldquo;Dependency Injection&amp;rdquo;, but can&amp;rsquo;t do anything with it directly? Then today&amp;rsquo;s post is for you!
I will introduce you to the principle, functionality and the types of dependency injection. Finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to write a simple IoC container. And don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you are unfamiliar with the different terms, I will explain everything, you don&amp;rsquo;t need any previous knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to VCS</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-06-23-introduction-to-vcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-06-23-introduction-to-vcs/</guid>
      <description>When you start learning to program, you rarely think about how you will be able to work on a project at the same time with other people. By the time your side projects take on larger dimensions or you work in a team, you will be confronted with the topic of version control.
Version control is basically the management of source code, so that several developers can work on the same files at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
