<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cms on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/cms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cms on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/cms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Wyam</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-11-02-moving-to-wyam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-11-02-moving-to-wyam/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been quiet for way too long here. I don&amp;rsquo;t really have an excuse for my absence but I&amp;rsquo;ve been kind of busy, both personally and professionally. But I&amp;rsquo;m planning to post on here more frequently from now on.
As always, trying something new in software development helps to become motivated and excited. In the last months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Jekyll as a static site generator to build this site. Though I enjoyed using Jekyll, I never really got into the Ruby environment and have been looking for something more familiar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Site Generators</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-02-10-static-site-generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-02-10-static-site-generators/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I moved this website from WordPress to Jekyll, but I never really explained the reasons. That&amp;rsquo;s why I want to discuss in today&amp;rsquo;s post the option of managing websites using an offline CMS or Static Site Generator.
CMS like WordPress are often ridiculed and devalued by their complexity or their overall structure. In the meantime, there is a variety of similar content management systems available, but they usually share the core functionalities and structure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
