<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xamarin on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/xamarin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xamarin on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/xamarin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dialogs in Xamarin.Forms</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-09-09-xamarin-forms-dialogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-09-09-xamarin-forms-dialogs/</guid>
      <description>If you already have a little experience in cross-platform development with Xamarin.Forms, you probably know the problem: Navigation between different pages works very well, but there is no easy solution to display dialog boxes overlaying an active page.
Today I want to show you how you can implement this feature in your Xamarin.Forms application. I have created an example project for this purpose, which you can download from my GitHub site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xamarin Debugging over WIFI</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-01-10-debugging-xamarin-apps-on-physical-device-over-wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 06:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-01-10-debugging-xamarin-apps-on-physical-device-over-wifi/</guid>
      <description>Xamarin utilizes the Android Debug Bridge (ADB) for debugging on physical devices, which are usually connected over usb. While this feature definitely is useful, it would sometimes be more practical if you could do this over WIFI instead.
Luckily, that is possible! You can simple switch between using USB and TCP/IP for debugging. To get started, you need to connect your device via USB to the computer you&amp;rsquo;re debugging from. I&amp;rsquo;m using Windows, so the commands I&amp;rsquo;ll execute the following commands from the commandline (which runs as an administrator), but since they are adb commands, they should be the same on Linux or macOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sideproject: CryptoFolio</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-12-10-sideproject-cryptofolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 14:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-12-10-sideproject-cryptofolio/</guid>
      <description>Today I would like to introduce my current side project. I&amp;rsquo;m currently developing CryptoFolio, an app that allows you to keep track of your investments in cryptocurrencies.
Functionality &amp;amp; MVP The first release of the application will allow you to view the current rates of the top 100 cryptocurrencies with the highest market capitalization. You can then add investments, where input, output and the date of the transaction is recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is ServiceStack and why should I use it?</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-23-what-is-servicestack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 20:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-23-what-is-servicestack/</guid>
      <description>This article is the beginning of a series of articles in which I want to discuss the basics of building web services and designing REST APIs using ServiceStack. This first article discusses the question of what ServiceStack is all about, the benefits of it, and why you should use (or at least try out) this framework. The following articles will then discuss the design of a simple service by using a simple example to illustrate the various possibilities it offers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Visualization for Numeric Values in Xamarin / DevExpress dxGrid</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-22-custom-visualization-for-numeric-values-in-xamarin-devexpress-dxgrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 17:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-22-custom-visualization-for-numeric-values-in-xamarin-devexpress-dxgrid/</guid>
      <description>The dxGrid grid control for Xamarin, which DevExpress provides free of charge, is a powerful feature for mobile application development. However, many of the functions are a little bit hidden. In this article I will discuss how to customize the display of column values.
In my concrete example my grid contains a numeric column, which can contain numbers with or without decimal places. I want these decimal places to be displayed only if they exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoupling Views in Xamarin</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-12-decoupling-views-in-xamarin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 10:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-12-decoupling-views-in-xamarin/</guid>
      <description>As a software developer, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably stumbled across old source code you&amp;rsquo;ve written from time to time and you&amp;rsquo;ve just been thinking &amp;lsquo;how the hell can someone come up with such bullshit?&amp;rsquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself as an exception regarding this topic and just recently had such a case, which I would like to document in this article. More specifically, I want to discuss the decoupling of views under xamarin. The source I use in this article is available on my GitHub profile.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
