<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>containers on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/containers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in containers on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/containers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dockerizing .NET Core Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-08-19-dockerizing-net-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-08-19-dockerizing-net-core/</guid>
      <description>I have already written two articles about the basics of Docker. While these should provide a general overview of you technology, I would like to illustrate a concrete application example today. I will show you the whole process, from writing a simple application to using it in the form of a Docker Container.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read my previous articles, you may not have the idea why you should use Docker at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker - Installation and First Steps</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-08-docker-installation-and-first-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-08-docker-installation-and-first-steps/</guid>
      <description>After outlining the theory behind container management with Docker in last week&amp;rsquo;s article, I would like to continue the topic in a more hands-on way today.
I&amp;rsquo;ll show you the installation and the first steps in Docker. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Installation Docker is available for Windows, Linux and Mac OS. For the download you&amp;rsquo;ll need to sign up for a free account.
I would like to point out that the Windows version is not intended for production use, only for development and testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-01-docker-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-01-docker-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>As a software developer, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard about Docker and perhaps already used it. But if you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you&amp;rsquo;ve been observing the topic from a distance with some interest, but you haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten into it yet.
In this article I would like to introduce you to the concept of docker and the &amp;ldquo;big picture&amp;rdquo;. This post will not be a detailed tutorial, but will give you an overview of the technology and help you get started.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
