<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:00:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing MagicaVoxel on Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-01-20-install-magicavoxel-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-01-20-install-magicavoxel-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>As a programmer with definite lack of visual skills, MagicaVoxel is a gift from God to create usable 3D models. Unfortunately, there is no installation option for Linux on the official website. With the help of Wine it is possible to use MagicaVoxel under Linux. And it really works great!
Installation Prerequisites As I said you need to run Wine. As stated on their landing page, Wine is a compatibility layer that allows Windows applications to run under POSIX-compliant operating systems such as Linux, macOS and BSD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Multiple Screen Sizes on Android</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-22-support-multiple-screen-sizes-on-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 21:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-22-support-multiple-screen-sizes-on-android/</guid>
      <description>Android runs on a variety of different devices. In order to improve the way your app looks on different phones, depending on their screen size and resolution, Android offers the possibility to use different layouts for different screen sizes. This is the topic I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss in this article.
Summarizing the Demo Application First of all, I would like to briefly discuss the app, the optimization of which will be discussed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Visualization for Numeric Values in Xamarin / DevExpress dxGrid</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-22-custom-visualization-for-numeric-values-in-xamarin-devexpress-dxgrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 17:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-22-custom-visualization-for-numeric-values-in-xamarin-devexpress-dxgrid/</guid>
      <description>The dxGrid grid control for Xamarin, which DevExpress provides free of charge, is a powerful feature for mobile application development. However, many of the functions are a little bit hidden. In this article I will discuss how to customize the display of column values.
In my concrete example my grid contains a numeric column, which can contain numbers with or without decimal places. I want these decimal places to be displayed only if they exist.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
