<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>challenge on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/challenge/</link>
    <description>Recent content in challenge on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why you should write your own Impossible List</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-12-09-why-you-should-write-your-own-impossible-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-12-09-why-you-should-write-your-own-impossible-list/</guid>
      <description>Writing down your goals is extremely helpful for really achieving them. With fixed, terminable goals with fixed intermediate steps, you make it much easier for yourself to really achieve your self-imposed goals.
Today I would like to show you a way to define your goals with the help of the so-called &amp;ldquo;Impossible List&amp;rdquo;. At first glance this list looks like an Impossible List, but it is definitely not: Joel Runyon, the author of the first Impossible List describes the classic Bucket List as a static list that was written at some point in life and usually none of the points written down really affect the life of the creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of Code</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-10-14-100-days-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-10-14-100-days-of-code/</guid>
      <description>You might be familiar with the following situation: You are in your first job as a software developer and spend less and less time with your own projects? Or the time you spend on them is generally getting less and less? I have the problem right now and I’ve been thinking about what’s causing it and how I can work on it. Well, the main problem, in my opinion, is that I no longer have the pressure from my studies to learn to take an exam, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Running</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-09-23-getting-started-with-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-09-23-getting-started-with-running/</guid>
      <description>If you had told me a year ago that I would run an entire Tough Mudder in a year, I probably would have made fun of you. Well, to be honest, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know about the existence of obstacle course races (OCR) of this kind at the time. If that were the case, I would certainly have been able to motivate myself quickly.
Briefly to my prehistory: I am in my early 20s and have tried various sports since my childhood.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
