<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <description>A software developers blog.
</description>
    <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mjurtz.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 19:51:31 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 19:51:31 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing Clean Code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of articles and even books about the art of writing clean code. But when exactly is code actually to be considered clean? Today I’d like to give you a brief overview of how you can assess and improve your code quality. I should perhaps note that writing good code, and therefore this article, is independent of the programming language used and is rather methodical in nature. However, for more detailed information, I recommend that you really get a book on the subject. The standard advice on this is certainly “Clean Code” by Robert C. Martin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all: What is clean code? Everyone probably has their own definition here, but there are a lot of overlaps. A key characteristic of clean code, for example, is good readability and maintainability. Why should the readability of your code be good? If you think about how much time you spend writing code and how much you spend reading it, you will probably get a ratio of 1:10. So if you make your code readable, you’ll make future work easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone probably knows the following scenario: You are pressurized by deadlines and tend to write “Quick and Dirty” code. Although the problem is solved quickly, in the long run this is the more costly approach. If this code has to be extended later, it will be much more difficult than if somebody thought about a suitable strategy before implementing it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You alone are responsible for your code. Imagine another profession: For example, in the food industry or as a doctor or nurse. If someone else told you not to wash your hands from now on to save time - would you do that? Probably not. And that’s exactly what makes your business professional. But what can you do to actually make your code more readable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use self-explanatory names. Variables, classes or methods have to directly expose what they do. Name methods and variables so that a class does exactly what you expect it to do after reading the source code. Also, avoid using abbreviations in your naming to make reading easier. Oh, and even if it feels tempting to name all variables, classes, methods, and the like after different Pokémon, don’t. Clarity is unfortunately more important here than being funny. Also, make sure you name similar concepts the same way. Suppose you write an API that receives data and performs simple CRUD operations - name all functions that perform similar tasks identically. For example, choose Insert, Add, or Append for creating new objects, but don’t mix these names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your code should speak for itself. This does not mean that you have to avoid comments completely. However, comments are often used when the purpose of the code is not clear. The problem here is very often that the code is changed, but the corresponding comment remains, and thus provides wrong information. So if you are in the process of writing a comment, think about whether it really makes sense or whether you should revise the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is another point regarding naming, especially for methods and functions: The single-responsibility principle. A method should do exactly one thing, and it should be done well. If you have a method that creates and returns an instance of a class with default values, that method should not add the object to a collection of objects of that class as well. Each method has exactly one task. If your method takes 5 arguments, it might probably do more than one thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write tests. I confess myself guilty of doing too little of this, but write automated tests. Not just to sleep better before releases. Write unit tests to validate individual parts of your application and combine them using integration tests. Of course, you can also add other test categories like UI testing, but I think you should start small: Anything is better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practice, practice, practice. This list is not complete, not at all. But it is certainly a good start. To write clean code, it’s all about practice. Look at other people’s source code. Ask developers to look at your code and give you feedback. You will notice if your code is good and internalize the important characteristics all by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/12/writing-clean-code</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/12/writing-clean-code</guid>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>software</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>methodology</category>
        
        
        <category>development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some Updates about this Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, today just a short note on a few changes to my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically I planned to take up various topics in the area of software development and to capture my thoughts on this blog. However, as you may have noticed, I have published a lot about other subjects lately. I want to return to my roots on this site, so I decided to set up a separate blog. From now on you will only find posts on software development and related topics on this blog. Sports-related posts will now be posted to mjurtz.com/triblog or triblog.mjurtz.com as soon as I get the subdomain set up correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your attention, regular posts will follow!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/12/website-update</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/12/website-update</guid>
        
        <category>website</category>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why you should write your own Impossible List</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing down your goals is extremely helpful for really achieving them. With fixed, terminable goals with fixed intermediate steps, 
you make it much easier for yourself to really achieve your self-imposed goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to show you a way to define your goals with the help of the so-called “Impossible List”. 
At first glance this list looks like an Impossible List, but it is definitely not: Joel Runyon, the author of the first &lt;a href=&quot;https://impossiblehq.com/the-impossible-list-is-not-a-bucket-list/&quot;&gt;Impossible List&lt;/a&gt; describes the classic Bucket List as a static list that was written at some point in life and usually none of the points written down really affect the life of the creator. 
So the goals are written down, but never reached or at least actively pursued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Impossible List goes a different way: It is not a list of entries waiting to be ticked off. The Impossible List continues to evolve. It describes things you’ve done, you should be constantly checking off entries. But you should also add new items. With the list you broaden your horizons and reach goals you didn’t think possible before. The bucket list describes the things you want done before you die. But the Impossible List describes your life. The Bucket List describes dreams, while the Impossible List requires you to take action now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is probably the most common answer from students to the question, what are their goals in life? Often you will hear something like “My goal is a good college degree, a well paid job and my own house”. But what happens when these goals are achieved? You are in the middle of life and suddenly have no goal to work towards. And off you go with the midlife crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the Impossible List comes in. Joel Runyon set up his Impossible List after graduating from college and it helped him run ultra marathons and much more. The Impossible List is not only set up, but also made publicly available online and can therefore be viewed by everyone. If you look at &lt;a href=&quot;/impossible/&quot;&gt;my list&lt;/a&gt;, you will also see that many targets follow similar ones, but with more difficult characteristics. This allows you to track your progress. This is the already mentioned developing character of the Impossible List.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone who wants to do many things, it is often difficult to set the focus. That’s why I use a status for my goals, where you can directly see if I’m working on this entry or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I have sparked your interest in the concept. If you want to build your own Impossible List, I suggest you leave room for iterations. Of course, you can also make your work easier by doing the whole thing digitally. I decided to use AirTable, the tool Joel Runyon also uses. Of course, you can also use any other table editing software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/12/why-you-should-write-your-own-impossible-list</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/12/why-you-should-write-your-own-impossible-list</guid>
        
        <category>self-disciplin</category>
        
        <category>motivation</category>
        
        <category>challenge</category>
        
        
        <category>goals</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning to program does not have to be easy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been asked all too often which programming language to learn first. And I’ve heard almost the same number of different opinions. Java or C++? Python or C#? Or maybe C?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-level programming languages like Java offer the big advantage that the entry hurdle is very low. You can quickly put together a functional application that does what it’s supposed to do. The extensive ecosystem allows you to make rapid progress and concentrate on the functionality of your software. But that’s exactly the point that advocates of programming languages like C or C++ criticize. These are generally referred to as “ more difficult “, which is due to the lack of abstraction of different system concepts. The most common example is probably memory management. While in C the developer himself is responsible for the allocation and release of memory, in Java this task is abstracted from the developer. Although this is an enormous convenience for the developer in later working life, there is a lack of knowledge about what is actually happening in the background for many developers who have only worked with such languages so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One often hears the argument that the processes in the background are not so important and that people should concentrate on the functionality of the software. But that’s the critical point: Once the basic concepts have been understood, the developer will be more careful with objects and will think twice about whether instantiation is necessary or whether access is also possible via already existing objects. In the end, this way of thinking has a direct effect on the performance of the application. Even if current computers are more and more difficult to bring to the limits of their load, this does not mean that this is a goal to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I would like to point out again that this article is specifically about learning programming. The later application is on a different page. With regard to the learning process, however, it makes sense to start from scratch and thus understand the most basic principles. Who should be familiar with the details of a programming language and the internal mechanisms, if not a computer scientist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my studies I also started with high-level programming languages (and didn’t touch any of them during my studies), so after my studies I had to invest some time to really understand the different concepts. Since you might feel the same way, I’d like to show you what I think is the best way to get started in programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think you should start with Java or C# directly, but also not with C. The reason is quite simple: With C as the first programming language you make slow progress and possibly lose the desire to learn quickly. But Java, C# or the like hide essential concepts and are therefore also not suitable for beginners. I think the best solution is the combination: Start with a simple programming language, with which you can make fast progress and see early what you can achieve. But don’t stay too long at this level and then switch to a challenging language like C or C++. Here you will learn the different concepts like variables, memory allocation, collections and so on. Once you understand this, you can eventually switch to higher level abstraction languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find this concept interesting, I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/cs50s-introduction-computer-science-harvardx-cs50x&quot;&gt;CS50&lt;/a&gt;, Harvard University’s computer science course, which you can take online for free.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/12/learning-to-program-does-not-have-to-be-easy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/12/learning-to-program-does-not-have-to-be-easy</guid>
        
        <category>learning</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>course</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Announcing MTG LifeCounter V2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With my LifeCounter app for Magic The Gathering, I released my first Android app on the Google PlayStore over two years ago. Besides my first release, this was also another milestone for me: My first real app. Over two years later, I am proud to announce a completely revamped version of the app. Several complete revisions have taken place in the meantime and I’m already planning the next one, as I admittedly tried to learn the MVP pattern with the app and now, a few months later, I’m completely dissatisfied and want to switch to MVVM. But that doesn’t really matter at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I announce the release of version 2.0, providing major improvements and enhancements. If the player only had the possibility to manage health points in a 2-player game so far, now up to four players can be served in parallel. In addition there are other features like a dice function for a 20-sided dice, a counter manager to organize counters on individual cards and the adjustment of various values such as the standard colors of the game areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/2018/lifecounter_v2.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;MTG LifeCounter V2&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2018/lifecounter_v2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have decided to offer a paid Pro version in addition to the standard version. Quite simply for the reason that in the meantime a lot of work went into the creation of the app and I would like to compensate at least parts of my expenses with it again. V2 will be released in the PlayStore in the course of the next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-player-mode&quot;&gt;4 Player Mode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the biggest innovation of the app is the 4-player mode. The mode can be started via the menu which can be dragged sideways into the app. The view adapts to the screen size. By default, for example, the color selection is displayed above the life points. If the screen of the device is too small, the points are hidden during the customization, so that a certain clarity remains ensured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game scores are saved in both game modes, so opening and closing the app, as well as switching between 2 and 4 player modes, will not result in any loss of scores. The 4-player mode is only available in the Pro version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;counter-manager&quot;&gt;Counter Manager&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another major innovation is the Counter Manager. You are probably familiar with the problem that tokens to change the attack and defense values of your cards are documented in a complicated manner using a tally sheet. This new feature allows you to manage the values of your cards in a simple and intuitive way. These values will also be saved when you exit the application, so you won’t accidentally delete any entries. This feature is also only available in the pro version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dice&quot;&gt;Dice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A rather small innovation is the dice function. Touching the screen displays a random number between one and 20, simulating a 20-sided dice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;energy-saving-mode&quot;&gt;Energy Saving Mode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Already implemented in earlier app versions, the power-saving mode provides a way for devices with AMOLED technology to darken the large areas during the game. This means the device consumes less power because black pixels do not consume energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introductory-screen&quot;&gt;Introductory Screen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’d like to briefly discuss another feature that I can provide thanks to Paolo Rotolo’s AppIntro library. The first time you start the application, you will see an introduction that demonstrates how to use the app and introduces you to the various features. Optionally, this introduction can be recalled from the Preferences pane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions-answers&quot;&gt;Questions? Answers!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have found suggestions for improvements, ideas, or perhaps an error in the application? I’m always happy to hear from you, preferably by sending an email to feedback@mjurtz.com or via Twitter: @MarcelJurtz. And of course I’m always happy about every review in the PlayStore!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/11/announcing-lifecounter-v2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/11/announcing-lifecounter-v2</guid>
        
        <category>android</category>
        
        <category>app</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>sideproject</category>
        
        
        <category>android</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jan Frodeno - Winning Matters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Gold medal at the Olympics, world record holder at the 70.3 World Championships in Roth and a world champion title at the Ironman in Kona - Jan Frodeno is a name that certainly does not only ring a bell for triathlon enthusiasts. Frodeno is celebrated by the fans like no other. But who is the athlete? Today I’m reviewing his book “Winning Matters - Success through courage and passion” and try to find an answer to this question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frodeno starts the first chapters with a big portion of self-irony and calls himself “loser” or “linnet”. That in endurance sports and especially in professional sports a lot depends on attitude is nothing new, but who would have thought that Frodeno himself uses mind games to influence his opponents? Again, he makes it clear that (unlike many other triathletes) he doesn’t do this maliciously, but for fun and with a lot of humor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the book is written in a very personal and humorous way, whereby Frodeno especially in the last chapters deals very strongly with his mentors, and knows how to appreciate his family and his team accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the chapters Frodeno alternately describes the course of the Ironman World Championship in Kona 2015, which he won with a time of 08:14:39, as well as his curriculum vitae and how he became the person he is now. Already in the first chapters different character traits of the author become visible, started with absolute unwillingness to compromise. Frodeno is a man who cannot lose. Well, you probably guessed that already from reading the title of the book. I don’t mean to say that he can’t handle defeats in a sporting way, definitely not. But he does everything in his power to win. To achieve that, Frodeno always focuses on exactly one thing. Rather do one thing right than several things badly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point that is essential to achieve your goals is to surround yourself with the right people.  Show me your friends and I’ll tell you who you are. Frodeno trains with two training partners who constantly push each other. This casual competition creates small battles in training, and you automatically give that extra bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Frodeno describes a persons psychology as the crucial characteristic of a pro-level triathlete. At this level, the physical characteristics of the athletes are almost identical. However, a race is decided in the mind, which Frodeno describes in the course of Olympia 2008, where he finally wins gold after loosening a mental block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Ironman Hawaii 2017 he finally has to struggle with severe pain and is overtaken by Sebastian Lange, who wins the title this year. Frodeno still fights his way through the marathon and inspires the masses. In the book he describes how after this competition he received messages from many athletes and fans who motivated themselves and brought new top performances through this mental strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole book is peppered with anecdotes from Frodeno’s childhood, but also with many details, especially about the mental training of the triathlete. But Frodeno also makes some statements, which he fully supports. One example is his attitude towards doping, which he categorically rejects. But even with topics like unsportsmanlike behaviour like overtaking and direct rearsing, which forces the overtaken to slow down in order not to be punished for slipstream driving, he does not mince his words and says what he thinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the book is written very entertainingly and the almost 200 pages (+ about 30 pages with photos) are quickly devoured. Frodeno offers many insights and valuable details into the life of a top triathlete and if you are interested in triathlon or want to take part in an Ironman, you are guaranteed to benefit from the shared information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/11/jan-frodeno-winning-matters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/11/jan-frodeno-winning-matters</guid>
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        <category>book</category>
        
        <category>reading</category>
        
        <category>sports</category>
        
        <category>triathlon</category>
        
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Frank Thelen - Startup DNA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In his biography Frank Thelen describes the various aspects of his life. From childhood, skating, the first company foundation and private debts in the millions to successful exits, everything is included. In this article you will find a summary of some important points of the book, but for more details I suggest you take a look at the book, it’s definitely worth the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Germany, Thelen is certainly best known for the TV show “The Lion’s Cave”, but from an entrepreneurial point of view, he’s already done a lot. In his childhood he didn’t like the monotonous, uninteresting lessons at high school and stumbled over his grandfather into the world of computers. One day he brings home a computer whose hard drive little Frank accidentally formats one night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to correct the error, he reads the entire 400-page MS-DOS manual and finally gets everything running again. From then on the enthusiasm for computer science was unstoppable, and Thelen founded his first startup. Unfortunately, this goes into insolvency, whereby Thelen is liable with his private assets and is now in debt with one million euros. He agrees with the bank under threat of a private insolvency on a significantly smaller sum and continues to pursue his dreams to change the world with software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to go into all the startups he founded or invested in, you can find a detailed overview here on his website, &lt;a href=&quot;https://frank.io/de/&quot;&gt;frank.io&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, I’d like to address some of the issues that have been particularly attached to me and that, in my opinion, offer immense added value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;never-give-up&quot;&gt;Never Give Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the insolvency of his first start-up, Thelen developed Do. The application was designed to fundamentally change the way people manage documents and, instead of manual, directory-based sorting on an AI basis, to independently recognize the context of documents and make them filterable and searchable accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application has been highly praised by critics and downloaded countless times. But while the download numbers looked great, most people didn’t use the app on a regular basis. The change was too big, old habits are simply too strongly anchored in the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the rapid success stagnated, Thelen was forced to lay off 80% of his staff. But instead of squandering the product, he focused on the essentials: Do included a document scanning function that automatically recognized and cut the edges of documents. From then on, the team focused on this one part, which is now marketed under the name ScanBot. The technology behind it is licensed by the way and also used by several other providers (here you can get the &lt;a href=&quot;https://scanbot.io/en/sdk.html&quot;&gt;SDK&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;out-of-your-comfort-zone&quot;&gt;Out Of Your Comfort Zone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New heights can only be reached outside the comfort zone. Thelen makes this clear using the example of the television show “The Lion’s Cave”, where he was unsure whether he was doing the right thing until the start of the first season. In addition, it is essential for entrepreneurs to constantly question their own business model. So to speak, to be prepared to disrupt oneself. And of course this works much better with start-ups than with long-established companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ideas-for-the-future&quot;&gt;Ideas For The Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thelen concludes his book with various ideas for the future of technology companies in Germany. And he doesn’t mince his words. It’s a good thing that Germany offers hardly any support for start-ups and that German politicians in general have as much knowledge of technology and information topics as a piece of bread, is not exactly a world sensation here (of course there are some exceptions). However, it is clear that we cannot rely on politics for technological development in Germany. Thelen mentions various arguments for dealing with new technologies. For example, he mentions tax madness and legal framework conditions such as the Basic Data Protection Regulation as an absolute problem for tech start-ups and fears that Germany will miss the boat in the coming big IT issues. Instead, he recommends that new technologies be seen primarily as opportunities. Of course, there must be an easy way to object to data collection and processing by companies in a simple way, but must this option really be deactivated by default?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thelen says in his book bluntly what he thinks. But he does so in such a personal way that the reader builds a personal bridge to him and, unlike in many other books, sees the author on a wavelength rather than on a pedestal. The many problems in his career make it clear that it’s not necessarily the one million dollar idea that makes you successful, but the ability to stand up again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone who does something can lose. But if you don’t start at all, you’ve already lost. If you want to achieve something - just do it. And if you also want to be successful in this industry, but have no idea for your own product: Start solving your own problems. The chances are good that you won’t be alone with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/11/frank-thelen-startup-dna</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/11/frank-thelen-startup-dna</guid>
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        <category>book</category>
        
        <category>reading</category>
        
        
        <category>books</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Create Unity Skyboxes From 360° Images</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I want to show you how to use a 360° panorama picture as a skybox for Unity. As you may know, skyboxes are usually created from 6 images (cubemaps), with each image representing one of the sides. However, 360° photos usually use a so-called “Equirectangular” format, which looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/2018/equirectangular.png&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;Equirectangular 360° Photo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/2018/equirectangular.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in order to be able to use such an image in Unity, the idea of creating a cubemap from a 360° photo is obvious. But there is an easier way, which I would like to show you now: Cubemap: I start with my image, which I import into Unity. Then I select it and change the &lt;em&gt;Texture Shape&lt;/em&gt; property from 2D to Cube. I then save the changes by hitting Apply and then create a new material. I change the shader from default to Skybox - Cubemap and specify the image I want to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s almost it, now you only have to set the Skybox via &lt;em&gt;Window - Lighting Settings&lt;/em&gt; and already you have your image and can integrate it into your projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/11/unity-skybox-from-360-photo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/11/unity-skybox-from-360-photo</guid>
        
        <category>game</category>
        
        <category>vr</category>
        
        <category>unity</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        
        <category>unity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maximize your Productivity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you’re at the beginning of your career as a software developer, like me, you probably know the feeling that you’re being overwhelmed by everything you want to learn. Especially at the beginning it is often not easy to work productively and to learn why I want to show you which methodologies I have developed for myself. Even though I use my own experience, my approach is of course not limited to the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pomodoro-technique&quot;&gt;The Pomodoro Technique&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning I focused very much on creating as much as possible and hardly allowing myself any breaks. But this is not feasible in the long run, your brain needs variety and chances for recovery. One of the first tools I discovered for myself to tackle exactly this point is the Pomodoro technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method is based on alternating work intervals with regular pauses, but working between these pauses in a really focused and distraction-free way. By default, one interval lasts 25 minutes, followed by a break of five minutes. After you have completed four intervals, a longer break of 15 minutes follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pomodoro technique helped me on several levels. But the focus was not on the breaks, but on the focused work on a predefined task. I no longer jumped back and forth between different tasks, but divided my TODO list directly into intervals and could then stay with the current task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this technique is not a silver bullet. Especially in programming people often talk about the so-called flow state. This is the state when one is isolated from the environment and immersed in a task and can concentrate completely on it. It takes some time to get into this state, and 25 minutes is certainly not enough to work effectively in it. The Pomodoro technique is therefore less suitable for such tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of tools that you can use to make this technique work. On the one hand, you can use a smartphone app (which automatically switches to flight mode during an interval if you wish), but there are also browser plug-ins or other desktop tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule-your-tasks&quot;&gt;Schedule Your Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point I’ve built up in recent years is working according to a methodology. Do you come to the office in the morning and check your mails or the chat of your team to know what to do today? Take 15 minutes daily to plan your day and prioritize your tasks. It helps me enormously to plan my tasks instead of just doing what falls into my lap. I often combine this planning directly with the Pomodoro technique and define how many intervals I want to spend on a task. This helps me to make the planning more realistic and not to do too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use Trello for task planning and misuse the Kanban board a little by splitting the columns into weekdays, using cards for tasks and assigning units to them by tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eliminate-distractions&quot;&gt;Eliminate Distractions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final point is devoted to the distractions already mentioned. Do you know the feeling when you just had an idea how to fix a bug and then your phone rings? Such moments are, in my opinion, the biggest productivity killer. It’s best not only to set your phone to silent, but also to disable notifications on the lock screen. I’ve often caught myself checking to see if there’s anything new. If your lock screen stays tidy, the temptation to check messages or the like is significantly reduced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/10/maximize-your-productivity</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/10/maximize-your-productivity</guid>
        
        <category>learn</category>
        
        <category>methodology</category>
        
        <category>netcore</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building your first API in .NET Core</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I want to show you how to develop your first API with .NET Core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.NET Core is an alternative to the classic .NET Framework. In contrast to the .NET Framework, .NET Core offers a huge advantage: It is platform-independent and therefore compatible with MacOS, Linux and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this article is to build a small REST-based API, which will respond to HTTP GET-requests. Of course you can extend the project according to your own ideas and experiment around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;setup-and-installation&quot;&gt;Setup and Installation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all you need to install the .NET Core SDK. You can download it directly from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/net/download&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, where you will find two different links. On the one hand you will find the Runtime Environment, as well as the SDK, which also contains the RE, but additionally tools for development. Download and install the SDK for the platform of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, it is a good idea to use an IDE for development. You can use Visual Studio for this, or alternatively you can use Visual Studio Code or JetBrains Rider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m currently working on Linux, I’ll use Visual Studio Code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;create-a-project&quot;&gt;Create a project&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working with .NET Core, the command line is used a lot at the moment. One such point is the creation of a project. Basically you can use any command line interface here, be it the terminal integrated in VS Code or the Windows Power Shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first command you need to know is dotnet new.  This command initializes a new project, appending the type of the project. For each dotnet command, you can display operating information by appending &lt;em&gt;help&lt;/em&gt;. In the case of &lt;em&gt;dotnet new help&lt;/em&gt; you will be shown among other things the possible project types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to create a new ASP .NET Core MVC project. But I don’t want to have a preconfiguration, so I initialize my new project with &lt;em&gt;dotnet new web&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;adaptation-of-the-project--implementation-of-the-api&quot;&gt;Adaptation of the project &amp;amp; implementation of the API&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First the Startup.cs class needs to be reworked. I’ve made some minor changes, which you can find in the following snippet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-csharp&quot; data-lang=&quot;csharp&quot;&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;System.Collections.Generic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;System.Linq&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;System.Threading.Tasks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;Microsoft.AspNetCore.Builder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;Microsoft.AspNetCore.Hosting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;Microsoft.AspNetCore.Http&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;Microsoft.AspNetCore.Mvc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;Microsoft.Extensions.DependencyInjection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;namespace&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;ApiSample&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;Startup&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// This method gets called by the runtime. Use this method to add services to the container. &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// For more information on how to configure your application, visit https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=398940 &lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;ConfigureServices&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;IServiceCollection&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;AddMvc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;SetCompatibilityVersion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;CompatibilityVersion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Version_2_1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 

    &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// This method gets called by the runtime. Use this method to configure the HTTP request pipeline.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;void&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;Configure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;IApplicationBuilder&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;IHostingEnvironment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;env&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;env&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;IsDevelopment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;())&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;UseDeveloperExceptionPage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Enforce HTTPS for Requests &lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;UseHsts&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 

      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;UseHttpsRedirection&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;UseMvc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everything is configured, the API can be implemented. I want to build a really simple implementation that returns the status of the service. An HTTP GET request should be answered with an info message telling the caller that the API is running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all we need a model class, which I built as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-csharp&quot; data-lang=&quot;csharp&quot;&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;namespace&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;ApiSample.Models&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;ApplicationState&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Information&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heart of the API is the controller that handles the requests. So I add a new controller to my project that responds to GET requests via the &lt;em&gt;/api&lt;/em&gt; route. The implementation looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-csharp&quot; data-lang=&quot;csharp&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;namespace&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;ApiSample.Controllers&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;Route&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;api/&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)]&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ApiController&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;SampleController&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ControllerBase&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ActionResult&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ApplicationState&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;GetApplicationState&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;ApplicationState&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Information&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;API is running&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have already worked with older versions of ASP .NET, you may have been using IActionResult as the return type. Now you can directly use the generic class ActionResult, where the type in braces is the type of the model which is stored in the response. On the one hand, this helps you with the readability of your methods, since the result is directly visible. This in turn is very helpful if you use things like automatic documentation based on method headers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically the structure as you can see is kept very simple. And that’s it for now. Start your project with the command &lt;em&gt;dotnet run&lt;/em&gt;, you will get the address and port where the application is running. With a browser of your choice or a test tool like Postman you can now test the API. By calling the address with the attachment &lt;em&gt;/api&lt;/em&gt; you should finally get the expected status message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;further-information&quot;&gt;Further information&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article really only shows the information you need to get started with the topic. If I could arouse your interest, you can read on directly at &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/aspnet/core/?view=aspnetcore-2.1&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;. But of course there are also several other articles about the topic, let your creativity run free and just try a little bit around.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/10/your-first-api-net-core</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.mjurtz.com/2018/10/your-first-api-net-core</guid>
        
        <category>software</category>
        
        <category>net</category>
        
        <category>netcore</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
