<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximize your Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-10-28-maximize-your-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-10-28-maximize-your-productivity/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;re at the beginning of your career as a software developer, like me, you probably know the feeling that you&amp;rsquo;re being overwhelmed by everything you want to learn. Especially at the beginning it is often not easy to work productively and to learn why I want to show you which methodologies I have developed for myself. Even though I use my own experience, my approach is of course not limited to the industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Learn</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-05-03-learning-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-05-03-learning-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>How often did you tell yourself that you want to learn a specific skill and you either stopped while learning it or learned it but never managed to apply it in your workflow?
I bet you encountered both situations more than once. In this article, I’ll cover my method on how I learn new skills efficiently and actually remember the stuff I read.
In this post, I’d like to share my thoughts and experiences in learning new skilly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Stuff Done</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-02-21-getting-stuff-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 16:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-02-21-getting-stuff-done/</guid>
      <description>While being fun, programming is not easy. To be able to dive into a flow state in which you&amp;rsquo;re completely focussed on the topic, you need to cut off all distractions. With this article I would like to introduce you to my methods of working in a more focused manner and give you some tips that might make your life much easier. My experiences mostly come from the programming area, but the following tips can be extended to various other topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P2P Synchronization with Syncthing</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-01-p2p-synchronization-with-syncthing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 13:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-11-01-p2p-synchronization-with-syncthing/</guid>
      <description>Everyone has different programs and tools that they particularly appreciate. One of these programs is syncthing for me, so I will briefly discuss how it works and how it is set up in this article. Syncthing is used to synchronize files between different devices and also supports versioning of these files. Syncthing is available for Windows, Android and as cross-platform wrapper. I personally use it on Windows 10, Arch Linux and Android (via Playstore or FDroid).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation &amp; Self-Discipline</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-10-23-motivation-self-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-10-23-motivation-self-discipline/</guid>
      <description>During my participation in various software development projects, I have noticed one thing they usually have in common. While it is often very easy to find the motivation to start a new project, many of them end up unfinished or not in a way you would like them to.
Laying Focus As you can see on GitHub, I don&amp;rsquo;t see myself as an exception, where I&amp;rsquo;ve started a lot of projects, but only a few end up finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Organization and Increasing Productivity</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-10-14-self-organization-and-increasing-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 06:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2017-10-14-self-organization-and-increasing-productivity/</guid>
      <description>In order to get professional elements, side projects, sport and social contacts under one roof, I have recently been busy designing my daily schedule to maximize my productivity. this article presents the results of my reflections.
As a software developer it is almost self-evident to work on various own side projects, which in my case are currently mostly developed in the form of Android apps. Starting with an originally simple LifeCounter for Magic the Gathering, over smaller games up to the design of websites, my GitHub profile has meanwhile reached a considerable size.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
