<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jan Frodeno - Winning Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-11-18-jan-frodeno-winning-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-11-18-jan-frodeno-winning-matters/</guid>
      <description>Gold medal at the Olympics, world record holder at the 70.3 World Championships in Roth and a world champion title at the Ironman in Kona - Jan Frodeno is a name that certainly does not only ring a bell for triathlon enthusiasts. Frodeno is celebrated by the fans like no other. But who is the athlete? Today I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing his book &amp;ldquo;Winning Matters - Success through courage and passion&amp;rdquo; and try to find an answer to this question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frank Thelen - Startup DNA</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-11-11-frank-thelen-startup-dna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-11-11-frank-thelen-startup-dna/</guid>
      <description>In his biography Frank Thelen describes the various aspects of his life. From childhood, skating, the first company foundation and private debts in the millions to successful exits, everything is included. In this article you will find a summary of some important points of the book, but for more details I suggest you take a look at the book, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely worth the time.
In Germany, Thelen is certainly best known for the TV show &amp;ldquo;The Lion&amp;rsquo;s Cave&amp;rdquo;, but from an entrepreneurial point of view, he&amp;rsquo;s already done a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tim Ferriss - The 4 Hour Work Week</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-04-book-review-four-hour-work-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-04-book-review-four-hour-work-week/</guid>
      <description>Most of you may already know the book by Tim Ferriss. Nevertheless, I would like to hold my thoughts here, because some approaches and concepts have really made an impression on me.
The basic idea of the book is that you can work from any location and thus combine work and travelling. The modern definition of wealth is not defined by the bank account balance, but by the ability to freely manage one&amp;rsquo;s time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
