<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Wyam</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-11-02-moving-to-wyam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-11-02-moving-to-wyam/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been quiet for way too long here. I don&amp;rsquo;t really have an excuse for my absence but I&amp;rsquo;ve been kind of busy, both personally and professionally. But I&amp;rsquo;m planning to post on here more frequently from now on.
As always, trying something new in software development helps to become motivated and excited. In the last months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Jekyll as a static site generator to build this site. Though I enjoyed using Jekyll, I never really got into the Ruby environment and have been looking for something more familiar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Updates about this Website</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-12-16-website-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-12-16-website-update/</guid>
      <description>Hey, today just a short note on a few changes to my website.
Basically I planned to take up various topics in the area of software development and to capture my thoughts on this blog. However, as you may have noticed, I have published a lot about other subjects lately. I want to return to my roots on this site, so I decided to set up a separate blog. From now on you will only find posts on software development and related topics on this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching Blogposts in Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-03-31-jekyll-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-03-31-jekyll-search/</guid>
      <description>In one of my previous posts, I went over the details why I moved my blog from WordPress to Jekyll. So far, I really appreciate my new system, but I miss one particular feature: searching through my posts.
Since Jekyll is a static site generator and does not rely on a database for the posts, you can&amp;rsquo;t simply add a search functionality like WordPress does. So, I have to work with some frontend / clientside stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-03-11-moving-to-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 15:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-03-11-moving-to-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>I decided that it is time for some changes. When I started this blog, I decided to use WordPress. My goal was to be able to write posts without having to focus on anything other than actual writing. Wordpress was the tool of my choice due to its simplicity.
Nevertheless, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t always really happy with the CMS. Problems occurred again and again, mainly in connection with performance, loading times and general page speed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
