<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>self on Marcel Jurtz</title>
    <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/self/</link>
    <description>Recent content in self on Marcel Jurtz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mjurtz.com/tags/self/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Learning with the Feynman Technique</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-02-03-learning-with-the-feynman-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2019-02-03-learning-with-the-feynman-technique/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s post is about learning new things more efficiently, i.e. wasting as little time as possible on learning. I use the Feynman technique, named after the physicist Richard Feynman. Feynman was known for his ability to break down complex facts into their core message and to convey them very easily.
You certainly know the concept of being able to explain things to others in order to better understand them yourself. That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I&amp;rsquo;m doing with my blog and that&amp;rsquo;s also the goal of the Feynman technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Learn Anything Quickly</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-29-learn-anything-quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-29-learn-anything-quickly/</guid>
      <description>As a software developer, you are probably well aware of the feeling: You are overwhelmed by the amount of interesting stuff you want to test and learn. But I&amp;rsquo;m sure that this problem is also very common in other fields.
If you feel like me, you may read and watch various books, blog articles or online courses, but you won&amp;rsquo;t really keep much of their contents.
In today&amp;rsquo;s article, I&amp;rsquo;d like to help you to learn more effectively about the topics that really interest you, wasting less time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tim Ferriss - The 4 Hour Work Week</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-04-book-review-four-hour-work-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-07-04-book-review-four-hour-work-week/</guid>
      <description>Most of you may already know the book by Tim Ferriss. Nevertheless, I would like to hold my thoughts here, because some approaches and concepts have really made an impression on me.
The basic idea of the book is that you can work from any location and thus combine work and travelling. The modern definition of wealth is not defined by the bank account balance, but by the ability to freely manage one&amp;rsquo;s time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Step Outside Your Comfort Zone!</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-05-31-step-outside-your-comfort-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-05-31-step-outside-your-comfort-zone/</guid>
      <description>We humans tend to make ourselves comfortable. We take the easiest way we can find. But there are so many things we miss this way. In many cases it is the small things that make a big difference. Today I would like to show you how I have taken such a step and what has changed since then.
Photo by Jenny Hill on Unsplash
As a child I did athletics for several years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Learn</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-05-03-learning-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-05-03-learning-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>How often did you tell yourself that you want to learn a specific skill and you either stopped while learning it or learned it but never managed to apply it in your workflow?
I bet you encountered both situations more than once. In this article, I’ll cover my method on how I learn new skills efficiently and actually remember the stuff I read.
In this post, I’d like to share my thoughts and experiences in learning new skilly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Stuff Done</title>
      <link>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-02-21-getting-stuff-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 16:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mjurtz.com/posts/2018-02-21-getting-stuff-done/</guid>
      <description>While being fun, programming is not easy. To be able to dive into a flow state in which you&amp;rsquo;re completely focussed on the topic, you need to cut off all distractions. With this article I would like to introduce you to my methods of working in a more focused manner and give you some tips that might make your life much easier. My experiences mostly come from the programming area, but the following tips can be extended to various other topics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
